export const polishHistoryQuiz = [
  {
    id: 1,
    isActive: true,
    score: 10,
    question: "Indicate the correct sequence of events in the establishment of the Polish state:",
    options: [
      "Baptism of Poland",
      "Reign of Mieszko I",
      "Formation of the Commonwealth",
      "Election of Casimir the Great as king"
    ],
    answer: "Reign of Mieszko I",
    description: "The correct chronological order is: B) Reign of Mieszko I (c. 960-992), A) Baptism of Poland (966), D) Election of Casimir the Great as king (1333), C) Formation of the Commonwealth (1569). Mieszko I's reign and the Baptism of Poland are considered the beginning of the Polish state."
  },
  {
    id: 2,
    isActive: true,
    score: 10,
    question: "Indicate the correct sequence of events in Poland's liberation struggles:",
    options: [
      "Kościuszko Uprising",
      "November Uprising",
      "Participation in the Napoleonic Wars",
      "January Uprising",
    ],
    answer: "Participation in the Napoleonic Wars",
    description: "The correct sequence is: D) Participation in the Napoleonic Wars, A) Kościuszko Uprising, B) November Uprising, C) January Uprising."
  },
  {
    id: 3,
    isActive: true,
    score: 10,
    question: "Indicate the correct sequence of events in the development of Polish culture:",
    options: [
        "Recognition of outstanding figures",
        "Creation of cultural institutions",
      "Participation in international cultural exchanges",
      "Emergence of new cultural trends"
    ],
    answer: "Creation of cultural institutions",
    description: "The correct sequence is: A) Creation of cultural institutions, D) Emergence of new cultural trends, C) Participation in international cultural exchanges, B) Recognition of outstanding figures."
  },
  {
    id: 4,
    isActive: true,
    score: 10,
    question: "Indicate the correct sequence of events in the development of the Polish economy:",
    options: [
      "Accession to the EU",
      "Reform of the financial sector",
      "Economic liberalization",
      "Growth of foreign investments"
    ],
    answer: "Economic liberalization",
    description: "The correct sequence is: B) Economic liberalization, A) Accession to the EU, C) Reform of the financial sector, D) Growth of foreign investments."
  },
  {
    id: 5,
    isActive: true,
    score: 10,
    question: "Indicate the correct sequence of events in Polish diplomacy:",
    options: [
      "Establishment of diplomatic relations with the USA",
      "Accession to NATO",
      "Joining the EU",
      "Participation in international organizations"
    ],
    answer: "Establishment of diplomatic relations with the USA",
    description: "The correct sequence is: A) Establishment of diplomatic relations with the USA, B) Accession to NATO, C) Joining the EU, D) Participation in international organizations."
  },
  {
    id: 6,
    isActive: true,
    score: 10,
    question: "Indicate the correct sequence of events in the development of Polish theater:",
    options: [
      "Creation of the National Theater",
      "Emergence of new playwrights",
      "Performances of Polish theatrical groups abroad",
      "Celebration of the 250th anniversary of the theater"
    ],
    answer: "Creation of the National Theater",
    description: "The correct sequence is: A) Creation of the National Theater, B) Emergence of new playwrights, C) Performances of Polish theatrical groups abroad, D) Celebration of the 250th anniversary of the theater."
  },
  {
    id: 7,
    isActive: true,
    score: 10,
    question: "Indicate the correct sequence of events in Polish science:",
    options: [
        "Emergence of scientific discoveries",
        "Receiving Nobel Prizes",
        "Participation in international scientific projects",
        "Founding of universities",
    ],
    answer: "Founding of universities",
    description: "The correct sequence is: A) Founding of universities, B) Emergence of scientific discoveries, C) Receiving Nobel Prizes, D) Participation in international scientific projects."
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    isActive: true,
    score: 10,
    question: "Indicate the correct sequence of events in the development of Polish literature:",
    options: [
        "Recognition of Polish writers at the international level",
        "Publication of the first anthologies of Polish literature",
        "Emergence of new literary genres",
      "Participation in literary festivals"
    ],
    answer: "Emergence of new literary genres",
    description: "The correct sequence is: A) Emergence of new literary genres, C) Publication of the first anthologies of Polish literature, B) Recognition of Polish writers at the international level, D) Participation in literary festivals."
  },
  {
    id: 9,
    isActive: true,
    score: 10,
    question: "Indicate the correct sequence of events in the development of Polish art:",
    options: [
        "Participation in international exhibitions",
        "Formation of new artistic trends",
        "Creation of new art schools",
      "Recognition of Polish artists at the international level"
    ],
    answer: "Creation of new art schools",
    description: "The correct sequence is: A) Creation of new art schools, C) Formation of new artistic trends, B) Participation in international exhibitions, D) Recognition of Polish artists at the international level."
  },
  {
    id: 10,
    isActive: true,
    score: 10,
    question: "Indicate the correct sequence of events in the development of Polish education:",
    options: [
        "Introduction of new curricula",
        "Founding of universities",
      "Development of distance learning systems",
      "Recognition of Polish universities worldwide",
    ],
    answer: "Founding of universities",
    description: "The correct sequence is: A) Founding of universities, B) Introduction of new curricula, C) Development of distance learning systems, D) Recognition of Polish universities worldwide."
  },
  {
    id: 11,
    isActive: true,
    score: 10,
    question: "Indicate the correct sequence of events in the Polish economy:",
    options: [
        "Economic reform",
        "Accession to the EU",
        "Development of industry",
        "Introduction of new technologies",
    ],
    answer: "Introduction of new technologies",
    description: "The correct sequence is: A) Introduction of new technologies, B) Economic reform, C) Accession to the EU, D) Development of industry."
  },
  {
    id: 12,
    isActive: true,
    score: 10,
    question: "Indicate the correct sequence of events in Polish sports:",
    options: [
      "Creation of sports federations",
      "Participation in international competitions",
      "Performances at the Olympic Games",
      "Winning medals at world championships"
    ],
    answer: "Creation of sports federations",
    description: "The correct sequence is: A) Creation of sports federations, C) Performances at the Olympic Games, B) Participation in international competitions, D) Winning medals at world championships."
  },
  {
    id: 13,
    isActive: true,
    score: 10,
    question: "Indicate the correct sequence of events in Polish gastronomy:",
    options: [
        "Participation of Polish chefs in international competitions",
        "Emergence of traditional Polish cuisine",
      "Recognition of Polish dishes at the international level",
      "Creation of new gastronomic directions"
    ],
    answer: "Emergence of traditional Polish cuisine",
    description: "The correct sequence is: A) Emergence of traditional Polish cuisine, B) Participation of Polish chefs in international competitions, C) Recognition of Polish dishes at the international level, D) Creation of new gastronomic directions."
  },
  {
    id: 14,
    isActive: true,
    score: 10,
    question: "Indicate the correct sequence of events in the development of Polish fashion:",
    options: [
        "Participation in international fashion weeks",
        "Recognition of Polish designers",
        "Emergence of Polish brands",
      "Formation of new styles in fashion"
    ],
    answer: "Emergence of Polish brands",
    description: "The correct sequence is: A) Emergence of Polish brands, C) Recognition of Polish designers, B) Participation in international fashion weeks, D) Formation of new styles in fashion."
  },
  {
    id: 15,
    isActive: true,
    score: 10,
    question: "Indicate the correct sequence of events in the development of Polish cinema:",
    options: [
        "Formation of cinematographic schools",
        "Participation in international competitions",
        "Release of the first Polish films",
      "Receiving awards at international festivals"
    ],
    answer: "Release of the first Polish films",
    description: "The correct sequence is: A) Release of the first Polish films, B) Formation of cinematographic schools, C) Participation in international competitions, D) Receiving awards at international festivals."
  },
  {
    id: 16,
    isActive: true,
    score: 10,
    question: "Indicate the correct sequence of events in Polish history:",
    options: [
        "Formation of the Commonwealth",
        "Baptism of Poland",
      "First Partition of Poland",
      "Restoration of independence"
    ],
    answer: "Baptism of Poland",
    description: "The correct sequence is: A) Baptism of Poland, B) Formation of the Commonwealth, C) First Partition of Poland, D) Restoration of independence."
  },
  {
    id: 17,
    isActive: true,
    score: 10,
    question: "Indicate the correct sequence of events in the development of Polish identity:",
    options: [
        "Definition of national symbols",
        "Formation of Polish culture",
        "Proclamation of independence",
      "Celebration of national holidays"
    ],
    answer: "Proclamation of independence",
    description: "The correct sequence is: A) Proclamation of independence, B) Definition of national symbols, C) Formation of Polish culture, D) Celebration of national holidays."
  },
  {
    id: 18,
    isActive: true,
    score: 10,
    question: "Indicate the correct sequence of events in the establishment of the Polish state:",
    options: [
        "Formation of the Polish Kingdom",
        "Baptism of Poland",
      "Establishment of the Piast dynasty",
      "Creation of the Commonwealth"
    ],
    answer: "Baptism of Poland",
    description: "The correct sequence is: A) Baptism of Poland, C) Establishment of the Piast dynasty, B) Formation of the Polish Kingdom, D) Creation of the Commonwealth."
  },
  {
    id: 19,
    isActive: true,
    score: 10,
    question: "Indicate the correct sequence of events in the fight for Poland's independence:",
    options: [
        "November Uprising",
        "January Uprising",
        "Uprising led by Tadeusz Kościuszko",
      "Participation in World War I"
    ],
    answer: "Uprising led by Tadeusz Kościuszko",
    description: "The correct sequence is: A) Uprising led by Tadeusz Kościuszko, B) November Uprising, C) January Uprising, D) Participation in World War I."
  },
  {
    id: 20,
    isActive: true,
    score: 10,
    question: "Indicate the correct sequence of events in the reform of Polish education:",
    options: [
        "Introduction of compulsory education",
        "Development of education during the communist period",
        "Founding of the first university",
      "Reform of the education system after 1989"
    ],
    answer: "Founding of the first university",
    description: "The correct sequence is: A) Founding of the first university, B) Introduction of compulsory education, C) Development of education during the communist period, D) Reform of the education system after 1989."
  },
  {
    id: 21,
    isActive: true,
    score: 10,
    question: "Indicate the correct sequence of events in the development of the Polish economy:",
    options: [
        "Industrialization of Poland",
        "Economic liberalization",
        "Development of agriculture",
      "Accession to the EU"
    ],
    answer: "Development of agriculture",
    description: "The correct sequence is: A) Development of agriculture, B) Industrialization of Poland, C) Economic liberalization, D) Accession to the EU."
  },
  {
    id: 22,
    isActive: true,
    score: 10,
    question: "Indicate the correct sequence of events in the restoration of Polish independence:",
    options: [
        "Establishment of the communist regime",
        "Participation in World War II",
        "Proclamation of independence",
      "Fall of communism"
    ],
    answer: "Proclamation of independence",
    description: "The correct sequence is: A) Proclamation of independence, B) Participation in World War II, C) Establishment of the communist regime, D) Fall of communism."
  },
  {
    id: 23,
    isActive: true,
    score: 10,
    question: "Indicate the correct sequence of events in the establishment of Polish democracy:",
    options: [
        "Participation in the first free elections",
        "Adoption of a new constitution",
        "Fall of the communist regime",
      "Accession to the EU"
    ],
    answer: "Fall of the communist regime",
    description: "The correct sequence is: A) Fall of the communist regime, B) Participation in the first free elections, C) Adoption of a new constitution, D) Accession to the EU."
  },
  {
    id: 24,
    isActive: true,
    score: 10,
    question: "Indicate the correct sequence of events in the formation of Polish society:",
    options: [
        "Development of civil society",
        "Establishment of human rights",
      "Emergence of political parties",
      "Participation in international organizations"
    ],
    answer: "Establishment of human rights",
    description: "The correct sequence is: A) Establishment of human rights, B) Development of civil society, C) Emergence of political parties, D) Participation in international organizations."
  },
  {
    id: 25,
    isActive: true,
    score: 10,
    question: "Indicate the correct sequence of events in Poland's EU membership:",
    options: [
      "Conducting a referendum",
      "Accession to the EU",
      "Signing the association agreement",
      "Defining European integration policy"
    ],
    answer: "Signing the association agreement",
    description: "The correct sequence is: C) Signing the association agreement, A) Conducting a referendum, B) Accession to the EU, D) Defining European integration policy."
  },
  {
    id: 26,
    isActive: true,
    score: 10,
    question: "Indicate the correct sequence of events in the recognition of Polish culture:",
    options: [
      "Participation in international festivals",
      "Celebration of the anniversaries of prominent figures",
      "Creation of national museums",
      "Emergence of new cultural initiatives"
    ],
    answer: "Creation of national museums",
    description: "The correct sequence is: C) Creation of national museums, B) Celebration of the anniversaries of prominent figures, D) Emergence of new cultural initiatives, A) Participation in international festivals."
  },
  {
    id: 27,
    isActive: true,
    score: 10,
    question: "Indicate the correct sequence of events in the development of Polish art:",
    options: [
        "Recognition of Polish artists at the international level",
        "Participation in international exhibitions",
        "Emergence of new artistic trends",
      "Formation of artistic unions"
    ],
    answer: "Emergence of new artistic trends",
    description: "The correct sequence is: A) Emergence of new artistic trends, D) Formation of artistic unions, C) Participation in international exhibitions, B) Recognition of Polish artists at the international level."
  },
  {
    id: 28,
    isActive: true,
    score: 10,
    question: "Indicate the correct sequence of events in the development of Polish theater:",
    options: [
        "Emergence of new playwrights",
        "Celebration of the 250th anniversary of the theater",
        "Establishment of the National Theater",
      "Participation in international theater festivals"
    ],
    answer: "Establishment of the National Theater",
    description: "The correct sequence is: A) Establishment of the National Theater, B) Emergence of new playwrights, C) Celebration of the 250th anniversary of the theater, D) Participation in international theater festivals."
  },
  {
    id: 29,
    isActive: true,
    score: 10,
    question: "Indicate the correct sequence of events in the establishment of the Polish state:",
    options: [
      "Formation of the Polish Kingdom",
      "Baptism of Poland",
      "Signing of the Kraków Agreement",
      "Formation of the Commonwealth"
    ],
    answer: "Baptism of Poland",
    description: "The correct sequence is: B) Baptism of Poland, A) Formation of the Polish Kingdom, C) Signing of the Kraków Agreement, D) Formation of the Commonwealth."
  },
  {
    id: 30,
    isActive: true,
    score: 10,
    question: "Indicate the correct sequence of events in Polish history:",
    options: [
        "Establishment of the Commonwealth",
        "Baptism of Poland",
      "First Partition of Poland",
      "Restoration of independence"
    ],
    answer: "Baptism of Poland",
    description: "The correct sequence is: A) Baptism of Poland, B) Establishment of the Commonwealth, C) First Partition of Poland, D) Restoration of independence."
  },
  {
    id: 31,
    isActive: true,
    score: 10,
    question: "Indicate the correct sequence of events in Polish sports:",
    options: [
        "Participation in international competitions",
        "Performances at the Olympic Games",
        "Formation of sports organizations",
      "Winning medals"
    ],
    answer: "Formation of sports organizations",
    description: "The correct sequence is: A) Formation of sports organizations, B) Participation in international competitions, C) Performances at the Olympic Games, D) Winning medals."
  },
  {
    id: 32,
    isActive: true,
    score: 10,
    question: "Indicate the correct sequence of events in Polish politics:",
    options: [
        "Participation in international organizations",
        "Establishment of democracy",
      "Formation of political parties",
      "Adoption of new laws"
    ],
    answer: "Establishment of democracy",
    description: "The correct sequence is: A) Establishment of democracy, C) Formation of political parties, B) Participation in international organizations, D) Adoption of new laws."
  },
  {
    id: 33,
    isActive: true,
    score: 10,
    question: "Indicate the correct sequence of events in Polish art:",
    options: [
        "Participation in international exhibitions",
        "Recognition of Polish artists",
        "Emergence of new artistic trends",
      "Formation of artistic associations"
    ],
    answer: "Emergence of new artistic trends",
    description: "The correct sequence is: A) Emergence of new artistic trends, D) Formation of artistic associations, B) Participation in international exhibitions, C) Recognition of Polish artists."
  },
  {
    id: 34,
    isActive: true,
    score: 10,
    question: "Indicate the correct sequence of events in the development of the Polish economy:",
    options: [
      "Economic reform",
      "Accession to the EU",
      "Development of new technologies",
      "Growth of foreign investments"
    ],
    answer: "Economic reform",
    description: "The correct sequence is: A) Economic reform, B) Accession to the EU, C) Development of new technologies, D) Growth of foreign investments."
  },
  {
    id: 35,
    isActive: true,
    score: 10,
    question: "Indicate the correct sequence of events in Polish education:",
    options: [
      "Founding of the first university",
      "Introduction of compulsory education",
      "Establishment of adult education",
      "Development of vocational education"
    ],
    answer: "Founding of the first university",
    description: "The correct sequence is: A) Founding of the first university, B) Introduction of compulsory education, C) Establishment of adult education, D) Development of vocational education."
  },
  {
    id: 36,
    isActive: true,
    score: 10,
    question: "Indicate the correct sequence of events in the fight for Polish independence:",
    options: [
        "November Uprising",
        "Kościuszko Uprising",
      "January Uprising",
      "Participation in World War I"
    ],
    answer: "Kościuszko Uprising",
    description: "The correct sequence is: A) Kościuszko Uprising, B) November Uprising, C) January Uprising, D) Participation in World War I."
  },
  {
    id: 37,
    isActive: true,
    score: 10,
    question: "Indicate the correct sequence of events in Polish cinema:",
    options: [
      "Release of the first Polish films",
      "Formation of cinematographic schools",
      "Participation in international competitions",
      "Receiving awards at international festivals"
    ],
    answer: "Release of the first Polish films",
    description: "The correct sequence is: A) Release of the first Polish films, B) Formation of cinematographic schools, C) Participation in international competitions, D) Receiving awards at international festivals."
  },
  {
    id: 38,
    isActive: true,
    score: 10,
    question: "Indicate the correct sequence of events in Polish gastronomy:",
    options: [
        "Creation of new gastronomic directions",
      "Emergence of traditional Polish cuisine",
      "Participation of Polish chefs in international competitions",
      "Recognition of Polish dishes at the international level",
    ],
    answer: "Emergence of traditional Polish cuisine",
    description: "The correct sequence is: A) Emergence of traditional Polish cuisine, B) Participation of Polish chefs in international competitions, C) Recognition of Polish dishes at the international level, D) Creation of new gastronomic directions."
  },
  {
    id: 39,
    isActive: true,
    score: 10,
    question: "Indicate the correct sequence of events in Polish fashion:",
    options: [
        "Participation in international fashion weeks",
        "Recognition of Polish designers",
        "Formation of new styles in fashion",
        "Emergence of Polish brands",
    ],
    answer: "Emergence of Polish brands",
    description: "The correct sequence is: A) Emergence of Polish brands, C) Recognition of Polish designers, B) Participation in international fashion weeks, D) Formation of new styles in fashion."
  },
  {
    id: 40,
    isActive: true,
    score: 10,
    question: "Indicate the correct sequence of events in the development of Polish literature:",
    options: [
        "Recognition of Polish writers at the international level",
        "Publication of the first anthologies of Polish literature",
        "Emergence of new literary genres",
      "Participation in literary festivals"
    ],
    answer: "Emergence of new literary genres",
    description: "The correct sequence is: A) Emergence of new literary genres, C) Publication of the first anthologies of Polish literature, B) Recognition of Polish writers at the international level, D) Participation in literary festivals."
  },
  {
    id: 41,
    isActive: true,
    score: 10,
    question: "Indicate the correct sequence of events in the development of Polish art:",
    options: [
      "Creation of new art schools",
      "Participation in international exhibitions",
      "Formation of new artistic trends",
      "Recognition of Polish artists at the international level"
    ],
    answer: "Creation of new art schools",
    description: "The correct sequence is: A) Creation of new art schools, C) Formation of new artistic trends, B) Participation in international exhibitions, D) Recognition of Polish artists at the international level."
  },
  {
    id: 42,
    isActive: true,
    score: 10,
    question: "Indicate the correct sequence of events in the development of Polish education:",
    options: [
      "Founding of universities",
      "Introduction of new curricula",
      "Development of distance learning systems",
      "Recognition of Polish universities worldwide"
    ],
    answer: "Founding of universities",
    description: "The correct sequence is: A) Founding of universities, B) Introduction of new curricula, C) Development of distance learning systems, D) Recognition of Polish universities worldwide."
  },
  {
    id: 43,
    isActive: true,
    score: 10,
    question: "Indicate the correct sequence of events in the Polish economy:",
    options: [
      "Introduction of new technologies",
      "Economic reform",
      "Accession to the EU",
      "Development of industry"
    ],
    answer: "Introduction of new technologies",
    description: "The correct sequence is: A) Introduction of new technologies, B) Economic reform, C) Accession to the EU, D) Development of industry."
  },
  {
    id: 44,
    isActive: true,
    score: 10,
    question: "Indicate the correct sequence of events in Polish sports:",
    options: [
        "Participation in international competitions",
        "Creation of sports federations",
      "Performances at the Olympic Games",
      "Winning medals at world championships"
    ],
    answer: "Creation of sports federations",
    description: "The correct sequence is: A) Creation of sports federations, C) Performances at the Olympic Games, B) Participation in international competitions, D) Winning medals at world championships."
  },
  {
    id: 45,
    isActive: true,
    score: 10,
    question: "Indicate the correct sequence of events in Polish gastronomy:",
    options: [
        "Participation of Polish chefs in international competitions",
        "Emergence of traditional Polish cuisine",
        "Recognition of Polish dishes at the international level",
      "Creation of new gastronomic directions"
    ],
    answer: "Emergence of traditional Polish cuisine",
    description: "The correct sequence is: A) Emergence of traditional Polish cuisine, B) Participation of Polish chefs in international competitions, C) Recognition of Polish dishes at the international level, D) Creation of new gastronomic directions."
  },
  {
    id: 46,
    isActive: true,
    score: 10,
    question: "Indicate the correct sequence of events in the development of Polish fashion:",
    options: [
        "Participation in international fashion weeks",
        "Recognition of Polish designers",
        "Emergence of Polish brands",
      "Formation of new styles in fashion"
    ],
    answer: "Emergence of Polish brands",
    description: "The correct sequence is: A) Emergence of Polish brands, C) Recognition of Polish designers, B) Participation in international fashion weeks, D) Formation of new styles in fashion."
  },
  {
    id: 47,
    isActive: true,
    score: 10,
    question: "Indicate the correct sequence of events in the development of Polish cinema:",
    options: [
        "Formation of cinematographic schools",
        "Release of the first Polish films",
      "Participation in international competitions",
      "Receiving awards at international festivals"
    ],
    answer: "Release of the first Polish films",
    description: "The correct sequence is: A) Release of the first Polish films, B) Formation of cinematographic schools, C) Participation in international competitions, D) Receiving awards at international festivals."
  },
  {
    id: 48,
    isActive: true,
    score: 10,
    question: "Indicate the correct sequence of events in Polish history:",
    options: [
        "Formation of the Commonwealth",
        "First Partition of Poland",
        "Restoration of independence",
        "Baptism of Poland",
    ],
    answer: "Baptism of Poland",
    description: "The correct sequence is: A) Baptism of Poland, B) Formation of the Commonwealth, C) First Partition of Poland, D) Restoration of independence."
  },
  {
    id: 49,
    isActive: true,
    score: 10,
    question: "Indicate the correct sequence of events in the development of Polish identity:",
    options: [
        "Definition of national symbols",
        "Formation of Polish culture",
        "Proclamation of independence",
      "Celebration of national holidays"
    ],
    answer: "Proclamation of independence",
    description: "The correct sequence is: A) Proclamation of independence, B) Definition of national symbols, C) Formation of Polish culture, D) Celebration of national holidays."
  },
  {
    id: 50,
    isActive: true,
    score: 10,
    question: "Indicate the correct sequence of events in the establishment of the Polish state:",
    options: [
      "Formation of the Polish Kingdom",
      "Baptism of Poland",
      "Signing of the Kraków Agreement",
      "Formation of the Commonwealth"
    ],
    answer: "Baptism of Poland",
    description: "The correct sequence is: B) Baptism of Poland, A) Formation of the Polish Kingdom, C) Signing of the Kraków Agreement, D) Formation of the Commonwealth."
  }
]
